<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://harasiddh.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://harasiddh.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-01-12T17:36:03+00:00</updated><id>https://harasiddh.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">harasiddh</title><subtitle>Personal Website of Harasiddh Ganesh - also contains his blog &quot;Monk of all Trades&quot; where he writes about everything, including Economics, Politics, Culture, Sports, Academia, Mathematics and Computer Science. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">First Post Here</title><link href="https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/first-post-here/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post Here"/><published>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/first-post-here</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/first-post-here/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi! Welcome to my blog.</p> <p>I started a blog briefly during the first COVID-19 lockdown because like everybody else, I was bored out of my mind. Blogs seemed to be outdated though, and I decided to jump in on the podcasting bandwagon. However, with the ever increasing workload that comes with pursuing two undergraduate degrees simulatenously, I had to eventually call it quits - inviting guests, recording episodes, editing them and then posting them was all too time consuming, and the opportunity cost was not worth it at that time.</p> <p>Now, while my academics are still a priority, I believe it is also important for me to share my thoughts with the world. Everytime I see something amazing, interesting, controversial or even downright stupid, my brain gets overwhelmed. I write these thoughts down often using the ever handy ‘Notes’ app on my phone, but I also wonder how many other people would have similar thoughts. So while a blog’s purpose is usually to write about things other people are interested in, the purpose of this blog is for me to share thoughts that I have, in the hope that other people who have them would be interested in knowing that they are not alone.</p> <p>Thanks for reading this so far, and I hope you stick around!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[first post here]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why humanity’s progress rate has an upper bound</title><link href="https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/why-human-progress-has-an-upper-bound/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why humanity’s progress rate has an upper bound"/><published>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/why-human-progress-has-an-upper-bound</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/why-human-progress-has-an-upper-bound/"><![CDATA[<p>I pretty much think about everything using the concept of markets - whether it is about technology, dating, birth rates, health, pollution…everything can be modelled from the perspective of markets</p> <p>I was just thinking about the marketplace of ideas. The main reason I support free speech is probably not the moralistic argument of giving everyone rights, but the logical argument that this allows everyone’s ideas to compete in the marketplace of ideas, thus allowing the best ideas to win, and a subset of these ideas ultimately drives the human race forward.</p> <p>However, I was recently wondering whether the best ideas actually win? I was talking to a friend of mine, and he is among the smartest two or three people that I know (and I know a lot of really smart people). He was trying to explain something to me, and I was unable to fully comprehend what he was saying. This required him to ‘dumb it down’ for me.</p> <p>However, in the act of dumbing it down, the true essence of what he was trying to say was not entirely communicated, which he later confirmed. That made me wonder - how many market failures have we had in the marketplace for ideas? How many great ideas have we simply ignored, if not outright rejected, just because there weren’t enough of us who could understand it?</p> <p>Assume the broaden possible definition of human intelligence, and assume that the population is normally distributed. Also assume that people can only understand stuff that is at or below their intelligence level (which is a pretty reasonable assumption).</p> <p>If the society you live in supports free speech (atleast to a certain level), we can assume that it’s probably a democracy of some degree. Assuming that this democracy works on the concept of majority rule, then we automatically all ideas from the right hand side of the distribution.</p> <p>This is scary.</p> <p>Then one might say - what if you’re not in a democracy? Well, then assuming that we are in the beginning of whatever non-democratic rule is in place, we can assume that there is one person who is randomly assigned to play the role of ‘social planner’. Now, this person also has a certain level of intelligence, and hence, will automatically reject an idea that is not comprehensible to them.</p> <p>Again, scary.</p> <p>Both of these examples show that there is an upper bound on the rate of human progress. In a full democracy, this is the 50th percentile. Alternatively, it is the percentile of intelligence the ‘social planner’ is at. However, every human society is somewhere in between the two, so our rate of progress is upper bounded by something in between.</p> <p>Still scary.</p> <p>What is not scary is that we do not live in a world like that. Einstein didn’t need everyone in the world to understand general relativity. He just needed a small % of the human population who are close enough to his intelligence level to understand it.</p> <p>And assuming every human being has the potential to become more intelligent on a day by day basis, we can constantly shift this upper bound higher and higher by ensuring everyone has the opportunity to realise their full potential. The primary means of achieving this is by ensuring everyone has access to high quality education from a young age.</p> <p>There might be an upper bound on our progress rate, and we might never be able to overcome it, but that doesn’t mean we can’t progress at all.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[and why we can never truly overcome this]]></summary></entry></feed>