<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://harasiddh.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://harasiddh.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-06T18:58:38+00:00</updated><id>https://harasiddh.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">harasiddh</title><subtitle>Personal Website of Harasiddh Ganesh - also contains his blog &quot;Monk of all Trades&quot; where he writes about everything, including Economics, Politics, Culture, Sports, Academia, Mathematics and Computer Science. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The best set of New Year’s Resolutions</title><link href="https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2025/hardy-new-year-resolutions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The best set of New Year’s Resolutions"/><published>2025-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2025/hardy-new-year-resolutions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2025/hardy-new-year-resolutions/"><![CDATA[<p>GH Hardy, who was Ramanujan’s mentor, apparently sent the following list of resolutions to a friend via postcard:</p> <ol> <li><em>Prove the Riemann hypothesis</em></li> <li><em>Make 211 not out in the fourth innings of the last Test Match at the Oval</em></li> <li><em>Find an argument for the nonexistence of God which shall convince the general public</em></li> <li><em>Be the first man at the top of Mount Everest</em></li> <li><em>Be proclaimed the first president of the U. S. S. R. of Great Britain and Germany</em></li> <li><em>Murder Mussolini</em></li> </ol> <p>And ordinary human beings like me (and maybe you? Unless you’re the next GH Hardy) write something like <em>go to the gym every day</em></p> <p>I don’t think Hardy managed to achieve any of the above before he died, but atleast he failed at something big. Meanwhile, I couldn’t keep up with my resolution to drink 8 glasses of water a day (I drank 10 today)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[and why you can never beat it]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Post Here</title><link href="https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/first-post-here/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post Here"/><published>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/first-post-here</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://harasiddh.github.io/blog/2024/first-post-here/"><![CDATA[<p>Hi! Welcome to my blog.</p> <p>I started a blog briefly during the first COVID-19 lockdown because like everybody else, I was bored out of my mind. Blogs seemed to be outdated though, and I decided to jump in on the podcasting bandwagon. However, with the ever increasing workload that comes with pursuing two undergraduate degrees simulatenously, I had to eventually call it quits - inviting guests, recording episodes, editing them and then posting them was all too time consuming, and the opportunity cost was not worth it at that time.</p> <p>Now, while my academics are still a priority, I believe it is also important for me to share my thoughts with the world. Everytime I see something amazing, interesting, controversial or even downright stupid, my brain gets overwhelmed. I write these thoughts down often using the ever handy ‘Notes’ app on my phone, but I also wonder how many other people would have similar thoughts. So while a blog’s purpose is usually to write about things other people are interested in, the purpose of this blog is for me to share thoughts that I have, in the hope that other people who have them would be interested in knowing that they are not alone.</p> <p>Thanks for reading this so far, and I hope you stick around!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[first post here]]></summary></entry></feed>